SAM OAKLEY

09751 289441 sam@blork.co.uk sam-oakley.co.uk

22 Durlstone Crescent Sheffield UK S12 2TS

Profile

I'm an experienced Android and iOS developer, with over 9 years of experience working with bot platforms. I'm currently working full-time on native apps for both platforms. I've also released several of my own apps available of the respective stores, which have received many downloads and favourable reviews. I'm looking for a position which challenges me in new and exciting ways, and helps me grow as a developer.

Work Experience

Senior Software Developer (Mobile), 3Squared — 2013-Present
After a year with 3Squared I was promoted to a more senior position, as the
most senior mobile developer in the team of 5. In this role I have taken on
responsibility for implementing new code standards and an emphasis on
continuous integration. I have personally been heavily involved in the
development of over 20 applications (a mix of iOS and Android) as well as
3Squared's suite of open-source iOS libraries, known as the Peak
Framework.

Software Developer (Mobile), 3Squared — 2012-2013

In this role I worked across Android and iOS - the only developer with both skill sets - producing great phone and tablet apps for both platforms. I worked on many projects for 3Squared's high-profile clients, delivering quality software each time. During this period I pushed for the team to transition to more modern practices, such as moving from SVN to Git, adopting ARC in our Objective-C code, and implementing code reviews.

Android Developer, GMedia - 2011

The company had an existing iOS app with internet radio functionality and wished to bring this to Android. I developed a full native version redesigned from the ground-up to take advantage of Android features, such as interactive notifications and widgets. The application was easily customisable, allowing the company to rebrand and resell it to their many customers in the radio sector.

Web Developer, Websell Masters - 2008-2011

Worked to produce high quality websites, mainly focusing on the tourism industry. My role was full design and development of the sites.

Solo Projects

Solo Developer, Pretext (iOS) - 2019-Present

Pretext is a universal iPhone and iPad app for creating and editing text documents, with special support for Markdown syntax. I was dissatisfied with the available text editors, so I decided to make my own with as much system integration as I could. Pretext currently has over 49 thousand downloads and a strong review average.

Solo Developer, Pinner for Pinboard (iOS) -2012-Present Pinner is my main personal project - a universal iPhone and iPad app for viewing, adding, editing and browsing bookmarks retrieved through the Pinboard.in service. Recently updated for iOS 8, it currently it has over 17 thousand downloads and a strong review average.

Solo Developer, Pinner for Pinboard (Android) -2015After working on the iOS version for a few years I decided to port Pinner to Android as well. Supporting all the same features but as a native Android application.

Education

University of Sheffield — Software Engineering (MEng)

Degree classification: First Class Honours

The degree course focused on practical software development including building web apps in Java and Ruby on Rails, mobile apps for iOS, the use of version control, and gaining practical experience by developing projects in groups for actual clients. Other aspects included Natural Language Processing, which was the subject of a research paper written in my final year.

Skills & Languages

- Objective-C & Cocoa Touch, Xcode
- XCTest
- Java & Android SDK, Eclipse, Android Studio
- JUnit
- Python
- · Git & other DVCS

Publications

Sam Biggins, Shaabi Mohammed, Sam Oakley, Luke Stringer, Mark Stevenson, and Judita Priess. 2012. University_of_Sheffield: two approaches to semantic text similarity. In Proceedings of the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics - Volume 1: Proceedings of the main conference and the shared task, and Volume 2: Proceedings of the Sixth International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval '12). Association for Computational Linguistics, Stroudsburg, PA, USA, 655-661.